<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<articles>  
  <article>
    <title>About KT-EQUAL</title>

    <subtitle>What is KT-EQUAL?</subtitle>
    
    <body>
      KT-EQUAL is a new project designed specifically to exploit a decade of investment by EPSRC in
      ageing and disability research. It is a complex undertaking, directly involving experts from seven
      universities, but engaging with many more in the UK and abroad. The main goal of the KT-EQUAL consortium 
      is Exchanging Knowledge – Extending Quality of Life. What this means is that KT-EQUAL will be pursuing 
      many activities, working with stakeholders and facilitating knowledge exchange, in order to develop new 
      technologies and innovations aimed at increasing the quality of life and built environment of disabled and 
      older people. We plan to make a enduring difference by establishing an even stronger influence on those 
      who are designing environments and products for a world which is rapidly growing older and in which more 
      people are limited by disability or frailty. We will need to tackle those who influence specifications to 
      which designers work, the compilers of building regulations, British Standards, planning bodies, 
      manufacturers and marketing executives.  At the same time we have to find ways of influencing those who 
      are concerned with the adoption of those new technologies which can assist with the care of those who are 
      suffering from the effects of frailty, accident or illness.

      By April 2009, KT-EQUAL will be eagerly recruiting staff and putting its plans into operation, by
      the summer it will be in full-flight.  However the show is already on the road with workshops,
      meetings and vigorous representation of the interests of older and disabled people to policy makers
      and politicians.

      KT-EQUAL is in transition from a previous project named SPARC. Through the EQUAL Network
      and more recently SPARC (funded jointly by EPSRC and BBSRC), researchers throughout the UK
      have become familiar with the realities of growing older, frailty and disability. They know that these
      do not respect the boundaries of the scientific disciplines. Seeking out solutions, improving quality
      of life and well-being, requires multidisciplinary research teams, engagement with the many
      organisations and agencies which work with older and disabled people, and recognising the
      preferences, knowledge and expertise of older and disabled people and their carers.

      Over the last seven years, EQUAL and SPARC have introduced many new scientists to the exciting challenges 
      of ageing research, and have secured their long-term commitment to the area. They have helped to build a superb 
      rapport across many different communities of stakeholders and interest groups, by showing that ageing and 
      disability research can and does make a difference to the lives of people. This has resulted in an incredible 
      level of support, interest and encouragement in this next stage of getting research into practice. EPSRC’s EQUAL 
      initiative showed that by keeping researchers close to research users and beneficiaries as well as ensuring that
      they were networked to policy makers, major improvements, locally and nationally, could be achieved very quickly. 
      EQUAL has had a significant influence on official regulations, standards, good practice and, importantly, 
      expectations about the quality of the built environment, about the design of products and systems, and about the 
      support which information technologies can provide to older and disabled people, in good and in poor health.
    </body>
    
    <subtitle>What are SPARC, EPSRC and BBSRC?</subtitle>

    <body>
      ##SPARC

      SPARC, which formally finished with the end of funding support in December 2008, is a unique venture which has aimed
      to ensure that older people benefit from advances in science and technology. SPARC is stimulating ageing research
      in three ways. Firstly, it has showcased the latest research findings from design, engineering and biology to all
      stakeholders in older people’s issues and it has listened to the issues raised by practitioners and by older people
      about the realities of ageing. Secondly, it has lobbied policy makers about the needs of older people and how these
      needs can be met and quality of life enhanced through the pursuit and application of research. Thirdly, it has provided
      pump-priming funds to newcomers to ageing research. SPARC awards were highly sought after as they have provided an
      accelerated path into ageing research. SPARC was supported by a single joint grant from BBSRC and EPSRC and was managed 
      by members of the research community.
      <!--May want to include link to SPARC website, url: http://www.sparc.ac.uk/ -->

      ##EPSRC

      The Engineering and Physical Sciences Research Council.

      EPSRC is the main UK government agency for funding research and training in engineering and the physical sciences, investing more
      than £800 million a year in a broad range of subjects – from mathematics to materials science, and from information
      technology to structural engineering.

      EPSRC contributed a £1,763,400 grant to the SPARC project.
      (Taken from the EPSRC website)
      <!--May want to include link to EPSRC website, url: http://www.epsrc.ac.uk/ -->

      ##BBSRC

      The Biotechnology and Biological Sciences Research Council.

      The BBSRC's mission is to promote and support, by any means, high-quality basic, strategic and applied research and related 
      postgraduate training relating to the understanding and exploitation of biological systems.
      
      To advance knowledge and technology (including the promotion and support of the exploitation of research outcomes), and 
      provide trained scientists and engineers, which meet the needs of users and beneficiaries (including the agriculture, 
      bioprocessing, chemical, food, healthcare, pharmaceutical and other biotechnological related industries), thereby contributing 
      to the economic competitiveness of the United Kingdom and the quality of life.
      (Taken from the BBSRC website)
      <!--May want to include link to BBSRC website, url http://www.bbsrc.ac.uk/ -->
    </body>

    <subtitle>Who are the main people involved?</subtitle>

    <body>
      <person>
        <!--Insert profile image for Gail Mountain here -->
        <name>Gail Mountain</name>
        <email>g.a.mountain@shu.ac.uk</email>
        <position>
          Professor of Occupational Therapy Research
          Sheffield Hallam University
          Principal Director KT-EQUAL
        </position>
        <field>Rehabilitation &amp; Self-Management</field>
      </person>

      <person>
        <!--Insert profile image for Leela Damordaran here -->
        <name>Leela Damodaran</name>
        <email>l.damodaran@lboro.ac.uk</email>
        <position>
          Professor of Participative Design and Change Management
          Loughborough University
        </position>
        <field>Independent living</field>
      </person>

      <person>
        <!--Insert profile image for Rachel McCrindle here -->
        <name>Rachel McCrindle</name>
        <email>r.j.mccrindle@reading.ac.uk</email>
        <position>
          Professor of Computer and Human Interaction
          University of Reading
        </position>
        <field>Health &amp; wellbeing</field>
      </person>

      <person>
        <!--Insert profile image for Catherine Ward Thomson here -->
        <name>Catharine Ward Thompson</name>
        <email>c.ward-thompson@eca.ac.uk</email>
        <position>
          Research Professor of Landscape Architecture,
          Edinburgh College of Art &amp; University of Edinburgh
        </position>
        <field>Built environment</field>
      </person>

      <person>
        <!--Insert profile image for John Clarkson here -->
        <name>John Clarkson</name>
        <email>pjc10@eng.cam.ac.uk</email>
        <position>
          Professor of Engineering Design University of Cambridge
          Director KT-EQUAL
        </position>
        <field>Inclusive design</field>
      </person>

      <person>
        <!--Insert profile image for Christopher Eccleston here -->
        <name>Christopher Eccleston</name>
        <email>c.eccleston@bath.ac.uk</email>
        <position>
          Professor of Psychology
          Director, Centre Pain Research
          University of Bath
        </position>
        <field>Self-management</field>
      </person>

      <person>
        <!--Insert profile image for Trevor Cox here -->
        <name>Trevor Cox</name>
        <email>t.j.cox@salford.ac.uk</email>
        <position>
          Professor of Acoustic Engineering University of Salford
          EPSRC Senior Media Fellow
        </position>
        <field>Developing research capacity</field>
      </person>

      <person>
        <!--Insert profile image for Peter Lansley here -->
        <name>Peter Lansley</name>
        <email>p.r.lansley@reading.ac.uk</email>
        <position>
          Professor of Construction Management
          Continuity Director KT-EQUAL
        </position>
      </person>

      <person>
        <!--Insert profile image for Verity Smith here -->
        <name>Verity Smith</name>
        <email>h.v.smith@reading.ac.uk</email>
        <position>
          University of Reading
          Continuity Coordinator KT-EQUAL
        </position>
      </person>
    </body>
    <subtitle>Contact Information</subtitle>

    <body>
      <contact>
        ##For media enquiries please contact
        
        <name>Dr Lucy Chappell, Publicity Officer, SPARC</name>
        <email>l.chappell@reading.ac.uk</email>
        
        <address>
          URS Building
          The University of Reading
          Whiteknights
          PO Box 219
          Reading RG6 6AW
          United Kingdom
        </address>
        
        <telephone>+44 118 378 7179</telephone>
        <telephone>+44 118 378 7391</telephone>
        <fax>+44 118 931 3856</fax>
      </contact>

      <contact>
        ##For design and engineering related enquiries please contact
        
        <name>Professor Peter Lansley, Director, SPARC</name>
        <email>p.r.lansley@reading.ac.uk</email>

        <name>Miss Verity Smith, Co-ordinator, SPARC</name>
        <email>h.v.smith@reading.ac.uk</email>

        <address>
          School of Construction Management and Engineering
          URS Building
          The University of Reading
          Whiteknights
          PO Box 219
          Reading RG6 6AW
          United Kingdom
        </address>

        <telephone>+44 118 378 7179</telephone>
        <fax>+44 118 931 3856</fax>
      </contact>

      <contact>
        ##For biological and biotechnology related enquiries please contact
        
        <name>Dr Richard Faragher, Director, SPARC </name>
        <email>r.g.a.faragher@brighton.ac.uk</email>

        <address>
          School of Pharmacy and Biomolecular Science
          University of Brighton
          Room 807, 8th Floor
          Cockcroft Building
          Moulescoomb
          Brighton BN2 4GJ
          United Kingdom
        </address>

        <telephone>+44 1273 642124</telephone>
        <fax>+44 1273 679333</fax>
      </contact>

      <contact>
        ##Research Council Representatives
        
        <name>Dr Louisa Jenkin</name>
        <email>louisa.jenkin@bbsrc.ac.uk</email>

        <address>
          BBSRC
          Polaris House
          North Star Avenue
          Swindon SN2 1UH
          United Kingdom
        </address>

        <name>Ms Linda Sayers</name>
        <email>linda.sayers@epsrc.ac.uk</email>

        <address>
          EPSRC
          Polaris House
          North Star Avenue
          Swindon SN2 1ET
          United Kingdom
        </address>
      </contact>

      For general enquiries or if in doubt please contact Verity Smith at the Reading office.

    </body>
  </article>
</articles>

