<articles>
<article>
<title>Knowledge Exchange Small Grants Scheme</title>
<body>
The ESRC has a strategic commitment to encourage a two-way dialogue and collaboration between social scientists and potential research users throughout the research process. Through knowledge exchange, the economic and social outcomes of social science research can have a wider impact on policy and practice. 

The ESRC Knowledge Exchange Small Grants Scheme is a pilot scheme that provides funding for social science PhD students, researchers and knowledge transfer professionals to undertake knowledge exchange and impact generating activity. The scheme is not designed to fund new research but is explicitly for new knowledge exchange or impact generating activity that may include events, networks, policy briefings, mini exchange projects, online blog sites etc. or a combination of activities. We encourage applicants to think creatively about the format of the knowledge exchange/engagement projects they put forward.

The knowledge exchange activity must be focused on promoting the application of social science within non-academic communities and should help to facilitate the co-production and application of knowledge. The target/main audience of the award activity must be non-academic stakeholders within the private, public or third sectors.

Applications must demonstrate links to the ESRC strategic objectives and research challenges.

## Aims

The aims of the scheme are to:

    * Provide funding for knowledge exchange or impact generating activity
    * Promote the application and co-production of social science research to non-academic audiences within the private, public and third sectors
    * Facilitate networks and collaborations between social science researchers and non-academic stakeholders
    * Increase the opportunities for social science research to make an impact on policy and practice

## Funding available and duration

The scheme will provide between £2,000 - £10,000 of funding (non FEC) for knowledge exchange and impact generating activity per application. Only one application is permitted from the same applicant per call.

Co-funding and support is desirable, particularly from non-academic organisations and all costs must be broken down and justified in the application.

Knowledge Exchange Small Grants can be between one month to 12 months in duration depending on the activity detailed in the application.

Please note that the earliest start date will now be 1 April 2010. It is expected that the grant activity will begin no later than the end of August 2010.

## Eligibility

The scheme is open to all social science PhD students (restrictions apply - please see below) and researchers at all stages of the academic lifecycle. Knowledge transfer professionals based at UK Research Organisations are also eligible to apply. Applicants do not need to be currently or previously funded by the ESRC to apply but they must be based at a UK Research Organisation eligible for Research Council Funding at the time of application and for the full duration of the grant.

PhD applicants please note: The Je-S system will not allow PhD students to submit an application to the scheme as a Principal Investigator or a Co-Investigator. If PhD students are interested in applying they will need to ask their supervisor (or a relevant colleague in their department) to be named as the PI on the grant and in the 'Case for Support' section of the application the PhD involvement/management of the knowledge exchange activity will need to be clearly stated and detailed. The knowledge exchange activity must be related to the PhD research being undertaken and completed within the lifecycle of the studentship.

All knowledge transfer professionals that apply must demonstrate that they have academic support from the relevant social science department within their research organisation. This can be demonstrated by including a relevant academic colleague as a co-investigator on the application or attaching a letter of support.

## Application form

The pilot call for this scheme is now open! 

All applications should be made via the Research Council Joint Electronic Submission System (Je-S), and submitted to the ESRC by no later than 4:00pm on3rd December 2009.

Proposals must be approved with costing by the relevant institutional authority at the Research Organisation before submission to the ESRC.

*Please note: this is a different scheme to the responsive mode 'Small Grants' scheme. Please ensure you have selected the correct call in Je-S (ie against scheme Knowledge Exchange Small Grants) as your application will be office rejected if you choose the incorrect call*

## Additional Information
### Generic ESRC Guidance

    * [ESRC Funding Guidelines (PDF, 332Kb) ](http://www.esrcsocietytoday.ac.uk/ESRCInfoCentre/Images/ESRC_Research_Funding_Guide_June_2008_tcm6-27612.pdf)
    * [ESRC FAQ's on Impact, Innovation and Interdisciplinarity](http://www.esrcsocietytoday.ac.uk/ESRCInfoCentre/Support/esrcexpectations/faq.aspx)
    * [How to write a good application](http://www.esrcsocietytoday.ac.uk/ESRCInfoCentre/Support/research_award_holders/FAQs2/index1.aspx)

### Scheme Specific Guidance

    * [Call for the ESRC Knowledge Exchange Small Grants Scheme (PDF, 104Kb)](http://www.esrcsocietytoday.ac.uk/ESRCInfoCentre/Images/Call%20for%20the%20Knowledge%20Exchange%20Small%20Grants%20Scheme_tcm6-34784.pdf)
    * [Knowledge Exchange Small Grants Scheme - Scheme Guidance (PDF, 124Kb)](http://www.esrcsocietytoday.ac.uk/ESRCInfoCentre/Images/ESRC%20Knowledge%20Exchange%20Small%20Grants%20Scheme%20Guidance_tcm6-34793.pdf)
    * [Knowledge Exchange Small Grants Scheme - Je-S Call Guidance Notes (PDF, 156Kb)](http://www.esrcsocietytoday.ac.uk/ESRCInfoCentre/Images/Knowledge%20Exchange%20Small%20Grants%20Scheme%20-%20JeS%20Call%20Guidance%20Notes_tcm6-34794.pdf)
    * [Knowledge Exchange Small Grants Scheme FAQ's (PDF, 92Kb)](http://www.esrcsocietytoday.ac.uk/ESRCInfoCentre/Images/Knowledge%20Exchange%20Small%20Grants%20Scheme%20FAQ%27s_tcm6-34795.pdf)

### Enquiries and Queries:

    * Je-S Application Queries: Je-S Helpdesk [JeSHelp@rcuk.ac.uk](mailto:JeSHelp@rcuk.ac.uk) or Tel: 01793 444164 
    * Scheme Queries: Kirsty Johnson, Knowledge Transfer Manager ([kirsty.johnson@esrc.ac.uk](mailto:kirsty.johnson@esrc.ac.uk))
</body>
<date>2009</date>
<publisher>ESRC Society</publisher>
<url>http://www.esrcsocietytoday.ac.uk/ESRCInfoCentre/KnowledgeExch/KESmallGrants.aspx</url>
</article>
</articles>